<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zewen Zhang</title>
    <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Zewen Zhang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 18:48:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/last-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 18:48:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/last-post/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce my final project: Covid-19 in US-case and individual level analysis.
At the beginning of the project, we start with preparing the data. There are four major part of the data our projects: policy data, hospital data, individual data as well as population data.
The data I collected is population data from United States Census Bureau, American Community Survey 1-Year Data (2005-2019). This dataset includes state level population data, describing the number of cases of female/male under each group for each state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classfication of Insects Images by Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/insects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 20:57:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/insects/</guid>
      <description>In this post, i&amp;rsquo;d like to give a description of how I train a deep larning model to classify insects: beetles, cockroaches and dragonflies with given train and test sets of images.
Firstly, I read few of the images randomly, and theses images have different sizes. For coinvenience, I transformed them into the same size, then tranformed images into np.array
After the transformation from image into np.array, the shape of the train/test dataset should be same as the numbers of images under each file in the original image folder:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Streamlit app</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/first_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 18:59:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/first_app/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will describe how I used streamlit to generate a simple app for my visualization of data of PhDs awarded in the US from website(https://ncses.nsf.gov/pubs/nsf19301/data).
Firstly, I used python to open the excel file I downloaded (Doctorate recipients from U.S. colleges and universities: 1958–2017). And I replaced the &amp;lsquo;-&amp;rsquo; into 0 for the first of the change rate column since the first year doesn&amp;rsquo;t has previous year. I display the table on the app and it looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Starwars</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-fifth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 17:11:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-fifth-post/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a short description of how I scrapped star wars&amp;rsquo; api and find the oldest person (or robot or alien) and list the titles of all the films they appeared in by using Python.
The first step is using function &amp;lsquo;requests&amp;rsquo; to scrub the data from the &amp;lsquo;people&amp;rsquo; section star wars&amp;rsquo; api since the information I want to know is about the people appeared in the movies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLite Schema</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-forth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:05:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-forth-post/</guid>
      <description>In this post, i&amp;rsquo;d like to share how I created a SQLite3 schema to store this data in at least 3rd normal form (3NF), and then populated the tables. And I also use SQL query to find the names of all playlists that contain instrumentals.
First I saved the csv file as a pandas dataframe in Python, then I created 6 seperated dataframes bansed on it: Track, Album, Playlist_namne, Playlist_genre, Playlist, and Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 17:14:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will focus on how I visualized three datasets about Malaria Death.
The first dataset is called malaria_deaths, it includes the data of Malaria deaths by country for all ages across the world and time. It has variables named as “Entity”, “Code”, “Year”, “Deaths - Malaria - Sex: Both - Age: Age-standardized (Rate) (per 100,000 people)”; “Code” refers to the country code, and I renamed the last one as “Death_Rate” for future convenience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euler Problems</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 19:17:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>Problem 1: Dice Game (Problem 205, solved by 14,219) Peter has nine four-sided (pyramidal) dice, each with faces numbered 1, 2, 3, 4. Colin has six six-sided (cubic) dice, each with faces numbered 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. Peter and Colin roll their dice and compare totals: the highest total wins. The result is a draw if the totals are equal. What is the probability that Pyramidal Pete beats Cubic Colin?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Hugo to build my first blog</title>
      <link>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zewenzhang1007.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>The first moment that I saw the requirement of homework, which is designing my own website, I was really nervous: because I thought it would be extremely difficult for me to design a website within a week. But I realized it would be an interesting experience when I looked at the instruction of Hugo. I followed the steps, and I had fun playing with the theme &amp;mdash; Ananke. Ananke is one of the most widely used theme in Hugo, and it is also the theme used in the instruction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>